Carl Manikian Papers MS248
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Carl Manikian Papers
circa 1968 -- 2015
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
MS248
.2 Linear Feet 1 oversize folder
59.2 Megabytes
19 Digital Object(s) 19 digital objects comprising 19 files
This collection contains fliers, photographs, and an essay created or compiled by Carl Manikian (E1972, A1974, D1977). Materials relate to campus life and Manikian's residence in Carmichael Hall.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carl Manikian, 2015, accession number 2015.051.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series.
Biographical / Historical
Carl Manikian graduated from the Tufts School of Engineering in 1972, the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences in 1974, and the Dental School in 1977. He maintained dental offices in Lowell, Massachusetts and the Danville/East Hampstead area of New Hampshire.
As an undergraduate, Manikian lived in Carmichael Hall and was active in dorm government. He helped organize events in Carmichael Hall's lounge, including concerts, all night movie nights, dorm meetings, parties, and the First Annual Riotous Carmichael Extravaganza (F.A.R.C.E) in 1969. Manikian also helped promote these events through creating and distributing clever flyers. In the fall of 1974, Dean of Students Jim Steindler created the position of Social-Cultural coordinator for Carmichael Hall, and appointed Manikian to the position. Then in his first year of dental school, Manikian continued to live in Carmichael Hall and arrange for social events, including faculty lectures, concerts, and artist presentations.
As a resident of Carmichael Hall, Manikian was close to the site of the fire at Barnum Hall on April 14, 1975, and took numerous photographs of the scene.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photocopied handmade flyers for events at Carmichael Hall, including movie nights, dorm meetings, concerts, parties, and other events, as well as a poster and program for First Annual Riotous Carmichael Extravaganza (F.A.R.C.E), held in March of 1969 and featuring the James Cotton Blues Band. This collection also contains an essay by Manikian on campus life and Tufts history, and photographs he took of the fire at Barnum Hall on April 14, 1975.
Tufts University -- History; Barnum Hall; Carmichael Hall; University history; Alumni collections
- Carl Manikian papers, circa 1968 -- 2015; MS248.001; 59.2 Megabytes; .2 Linear Feet 1 oversize folder; 19 Digital Object(s) 19 digital objects comprising 19 files
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged roughly by format.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series is open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photocopied handmade flyers for events at Carmichael Hall, including movie nights, dorm meetings, concerts, parties, and other events, as well as a poster and program for First Annual Riotous Carmichael Extravaganza (F.A.R.C.E), held in March of 1969 and featuring the James Cotton Blues Band. This series also contains an essay by Manikian on campus life and Tufts history, and photographs he took of the fire at Barnum Hall on April 14, 1975.
  - Carmichael Hall event flyers and poster, circa 1968 -- 1972; MS248.001.001; .2 Linear Feet 1 oversize folder (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 3)
    This file contains photocopied handmade flyers for events at Carmichael Hall, including movie nights, dorm meetings, concerts, parties, and other events. This file also contains a poster and program for First Annual Riotous Carmichael Extravaganza (F.A.R.C.E), held in March of 1969 and featuring the James Cotton Blues Band.
  - "Barnum Burns and Campus Life", 2015; MS248.001.00001; .02 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s)
    Open for research.
    Essay by Carl Manikian on campus life and Tufts history.
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 1, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00002; 3.08 Megabytes
    Image of the fire at Barnum Hall.
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 2, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00003; 3.35 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 3, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00004; 3.28 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 4, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00005; 3.65 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 5, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00006; 3.31 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 6, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00007; 3.3 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 7, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00008; 3.39 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 8, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00009; 3.56 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 9, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00010; 3.57 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 10, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00011; 3.59 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 11, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00012; 3.51 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 12, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00013; 3.04 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 13, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00014; 3.35 Megabytes
  - Manikian Photographs, Untitled 14, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00015; 3.23 Megabytes
  - Pumper Panel, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00016; 3.37 Megabytes
    Image of the fire at Barnum Hall: pumper panel.
  - Sparks Over Ballou, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00017; 3.69 Megabytes
    Image of the fire at Barnum Hall: sparks over Ballou.
  - View From 3Rd Floor Carmichael, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00018; 2.83 Megabytes
    Image of the fire at Barnum Hall: view from the third floor of Carmichael Hall.
  - West Hall, 1975-04-14; MS248.001.00019; 3.54 Megabytes
    Image of the fire at Barnum Hall: West Hall.